Kenny Becerra Frontend Developer





About me

I am a software developer with a passion for frontend development. I have 3+ years of experience building web applications using Vanilla JS, jQuery, and experienced using frameworks like React, and Ember. Checkout my Github to see some of the Front-end dev projects I've worked on.



Skills

HTML/CSS

✓ HTML5✓ CSS3✓ SASS/LESS✓ Flexbox✓ CSS Grid✓ Bootstrap

JAVASCRIPT

✓ ES5/ES6 ✓ JQuery ✓ React / Redux ✓ Node.js
TOOLS

✓ NPM
✓ Webpack
✓ Grunt
✓ VS Code
✓ Git



Work Experience

Frontend Developer at Inxeption

San Francisco, CA July 2019 - Present

Contributed to revamp of company public facing website (www.inxeption.com) by adding animations and functionality using vanilla JS, jQuery, and handlebars.

Responsible for converting Adobe XD wireframes into functional web pages for multiple repositories, using vanilla JS, React/Redux and Ember/Redux.

Collaborated with product managers, designers, and backend engineers to resolve bugs and build new features in existing applications.

Built a development environment/toolset (using node.js, express, handlebars, and MJML) for developing cross email-client compatible templates for web app notifications and outreach.

Programmer at Pacific Gas & Electric

San Francisco, CA January 2017 - July 2019

Developed all User Interfaces for Third-Party Security (TSR) team vendor database using latest technologies for HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, Webpack, Babel, NPM, Jest .

Utilized Node.js libraries to automate team process and create tools to enhance email awareness campaigns, metrics tracking and reporting.

Developed Single Page Applications (SPAs) in Sharepoint using Semantic UI, jQuery, D3.js and chart.js for TSR team to access/modify backend database via Sharepoint REST Calls.

Perform ad-hoc frontend development requests for Cybersecurity crossteam collaboration and data access to TSR team backend.

Programmer at Pacific Gas & Electric

San Francisco, CA August 2015 - December 2016

Developed scripting solutions for Energy Procurement Support team ad-hoc requests.

Developed UI functionality for Energy Procurement System tools using SQL, and VBA.

Automated administrative tasks and workflows using VBA, Python, JavaScript and SharePoint Rest API



Education

Bachelors of Science in Computer Engineering

Florida State University



Contact

kennybecerra.j@gmail.com

https://github.com/kennybecerra

www.linkedin.com/in/kennybecerra/

